Guide to the International House Records, 1961-2007 UA.09.15.0001
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
International House records
1961-2007
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Duke University. International House
UA.09.15.0001
8.2 Linear Feet
The International House's mission is to assist international students, faculty and their families with orientation and acclimation, and enhance cross-cultural interaction through programming and community outreach and to provide advocacy and support for the Duke International Community. The collection contains some correspondence, clippings, directories of students and faculty, audiocassettes, slides, printed material, scrapbooks and information about orientation and other programs sponsored by the International House. The material ranges in date from 1961-2007.
approx. 4,500 Items
Access Restrictions
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
For a period of twenty-five years from the origin of the material, permission in writing from the office of origin and the University Archivist is required for use. After twenty-five years, records that have been processed may be consulted with the permission of the University Archivist.
This material is stored off-site; 48 hours advanced notice is required for use.
Provenance
The International House Records were received by the University Archives as transfers between 1975-2007.
Historical Note
The International House's mission is to assist international students, faculty and their families with orientation and acclimation, and enhance cross-cultural interaction through programming and community outreach and to provide advocacy and support for the Duke International Community.
By the late 1950s it had become apparent to University administrators that Duke's international students and faculty would benefit from an office set up specifically to assist them with living, studying, and working in the U.S. The Foreign Student Advisory Committee was created in 1960 by President Hart in an attempt to provide administrative aid to students. By 1963 the Committee had been disbanded in favor of the new Office of International Students. The International Office became the International House in 1964 when it moved to its own building on Campus Drive. In its years of operation, the International House has been a major sponsor of programs and groups such as the International Club and the International Friends program (formerly the Host Family program), as well as providing administrative services to Duke's international community.
Collection Overview
The collection contains correspondence, flyers, printed material such as newsletters and brochures, audiocassettes, slides, and directories. The material ranges in date from 1961-2007. More than half of this collection is comprised of subject files and subjects include the National Association for Foreign Student Affairs, volunteer programs, English as a Second Language classes, and other activities coordinated by the House. The paper "Decision Process for Study Abroad" by Masaomi Hayashi gives some statistical information about the reasons students come to Duke from abroad. The files also include publications and newsletters produced by other organizations. Flyers, administrative records and newspaper clippings provide a glimpse of some of the day to day operations of the International House. Directories of foreign students and faculty document the makeup of Duke's international community and include statistical breakdowns of individuals by country of origin or field of study, while advance information sheets completed by the students provide personal data (these sheets to do not contain protected information). Also included are two scrapbooks. Computer print-outs which contains personally identifiable information such as social security numbers were destroyed.
Related Material
International Association Records, 1961-1987
Duke University Archives
AIESEC, Duke University Chapter Records, 1966 - 1970
Duke University Archives
Clippings (information artifacts); Audiocassettes; Slides (photographs); Students, Foreign; Scrapbooks; International students -- Durham, N.C..; Duke University. Office of International Students; Duke University. International Office; Duke University. International House; Duke University. International House
- Subject Files
  - Administrative (memos, mailing lists, event calendars), 1969-1977 (Box 1)
  - Administrative (correspondence, event flyers), 1973-1977 (Box 1)
  - Africa, 1977 (Box 1)
  - Agency for International Development (AID), 1974 (Box 1)
  - AID Conference Workshop, 1978-1980 (Box 1)
  - AID/NAFSA Community Involvement Meeting, Chicago, 1979 (Box 1)
  - AID/NAFSA Correspondence, 1978-1981 (Box 1)
  - AID/NAFSA Project Material, 1978-1979 (Box 1)
  - Altrusa, 1963, 1977 (Box 1)
  - American Friends of the Middle East, 1976 (Box 1)
  - American Field Service, 1970-1971, 1975 (Box 1)
  - Arrival and Orientation, 1974-1975, 1978 (Box 1)
  - Arab World, 1974-1977 (Box 1)
  - Asia, 1973-1974 (Box 2)
  - The Asian Student, 1963-1974 (Box 2)
  - Australia, 1973-1974 (Box 2)
  - Baptist, 1977 (Box 2)
  - Brian Silver, Information and Statistics, 1983-1986 (Box 2)
  - Camping, 1975 (Box 2)
  - Canada, 1972-1973, 1979 (Box 2)
  - China Exchange, 1974-1978 (Box 2)
  - Chinese Student Association, 1971-1975 (Box 2)
  - [Duke] Chinese Student Association Charter File, 1980s (Box 2)
  - Christmas International Program, 1975-1981 (Box 2)
  - Committee on Foreign Student Affairs, 1973-1975 (Box 2)
  - Commonwealth Seminar "Muslims in Europe," 1980 (Box 2)
  - Commonwealth Studies Center, 1973 (Box 2)
  - Continuing Education, 1976 (Box 2)
  - COMSEC, 1975-1981 (Box 2)
  - Correspondence of General Interest, 1962-1975 (Box 2)
  - Correspondence from Internationally Oriented Institutions, 1959-1975 (Box 2)
  - Correspondence and Newsletters of Internationally Oriented Institutions, 1977-1979 (Box 2)
  - COSERV, 1972-1978 (Box 2)
  - Council on International Educational Exchange, 1978-1979 (Box 2)
  - Course Paper: Decision Process for Study Abroad, Masaomi Hayashi, 1978 (Box 3)
  - CROP (Community Hunger Appeal of Church World Service), 1975, 1978 (Box 3)
  - Duke University (General Info. and Policies), 1973-1977 (Box 3)
  - Duke University Study Abroad, 1963, 1977 (Box 3)
  - Durham Host Families, 1964-1980 (Box 3)
  - Durham Women's Club Picnic Sign-in Book, 1988 August (Box 3)
  - Duke University International Club, 1969-1973 (Box 3)
  - Embassy Correspondence, 1964-1976 (Box 3)
  - Employment, 1963, 1977 (Box 3)
  - English Conversational Program, circa 1973-1975 (Box 3)
  - English Conversation Class, 1975-1977 (Box 3)
  - English: Summer and Conversational, circa 1977 (Box 3)
  - English as a Second Language, 1973-1980 (Box 3)
  - Enrollment in International Living, 1968, 1973-1977 (Box 3)
  - Foreign Faculty and Fellows, 1980-1982 (Box 3)
  - Foreign Student and Faculty Information Requests from Organizations, Corporations and Individuals, 1961-1976 (Box 3)
  - Foreign Students at Duke, 1996-1998 (Box 4)
  - Foreign Student Office, Report, 1962-1963 (Box 4)
  - Foreign Student Service Council, 1974 (Box 4)
  - Foreign Visitor Schedules and Itineraries, 1967-1973 (Box 4)
  - Governor's International Student Day, 1964 (Box 4)
  - Graduate International Experience Responses, 2002 (Box 4)
  - Hill, John W. Foundation, 1969 (Box 4)
  - India Association of Durham, 1971-1981 (Box 4)
  - Information, Release of, 1960s (Box 4)
  - Institute of International Education, 1972-1981 (Box 4)
  - Insurance, circa 1975 (Box 4)
  - International Association of Students in Economics and Business Management, 1977 (Box 4)
  - International Classroom, 1974-1976 (Box 4)
  - International House Guests, 1967-1978 (Box 4)
  - International House Guests, 1978-1980 (Box 5)
  - International Staff and Faculty, 1975-1976 (Box 5)
  - International Student Service, 1971-1974 (Box 5)
  - International Wives, 1971-1977 (Box 5)
  - Iran, 1978-1979 (Box 5)
  - Japanese Universities, 1973-1975 (Box 5)
  - Memoir: Paul Perroud describes experience as a Smith-Mundt/Fulbright student scholar at Duke, 1955 (Box 5)
  - NAFSA (National Association for Foreign Student Affairs), 1972-1977 (Box 5)
  - NC Central University, 1972-1974 (Box 5)
  - NC Council on International Education, 1980-1981 (Box 5)
  - Receptions for Foreign Students and Personnel, 1963-1973 (Box 5)
  - Rosters (including foreign alumni), 1980-1981 (Box 5)
  - Rotary Club, 1965-1974 (Box 5)
  - Speakers' Bureau, Requests and Evaluations, 1975-1977 (Box 6)
  - Study Abroad, Solicitations, and Other Programs, 1975-1978 (Box 6)
  - UNC International Center Newsletter, 1974-1976 (Box 6)
  - UNC International Center Newsletter, 1977-1979 (Box 6)
  - Visit Reports, circa 1977-1981 (Box 6)
  - Volunteer Agency - Durham, 1970s (Box 6)
  - Volunteer-o-thon, 1977 Sept. (Box 6)
  - Washington, DC Youth Hostels, 1974 (Box 6)
  - Washington Post Fellows, circa 1978 (Box 6)
  - Welcome Picnics, Sign-in Books, 1976-1994 (Box 7)
  - YMCA, circa 1964, 1975 (Box 7)
- Orientation
  - New Student Orientation, 1967-1971 (Box 7)
  - Orientation, 1971-1975 (Box 7)
  - Orientation, 1977 Fall (Box 7)
  - Orientation, 1979 (Box 7)
  - Orientation, 1980 (Box 7)
  - Brochures, circa 1998-2007 (Box 7)
- Advance Information Sheets
  - Advance Information Sheets, circa late 1970s-early 1980s (5 folders) (Box 8)
  - Advance Information Sheets of Students Who Canceled, A-J, circa late 1970s-early 1980s (Box 9)
  - Advance Information Sheets of Students Who Canceled, K-P, circa late 1970s-early 1980s (Box 9)
  - Advance Information Sheets of Students Who Canceled, R-Z, circa late 1970s-early 1980s (Box 9)
- Directories
  - Directories, 1959-1976 (Box 9)
  - Directories, 1969-1973 (Box 9)
  - Directories, 1974 (Box 9)
  - Directories, 1975 (Box 9)
  - Directories, 1976 (Box 9)
  - Directories, 1977 (Box 9)
  - Directories, 1978 (Box 9)
  - Directories, 1979 (Box 9)
  - Directories, 1980 (Box 9)
  - Directories, 1981 (Box 9)
  - Directories, 1993-1996 (Box 9)
  - Directories, 1995/1996 (Box 9)
- Printed and Miscellaneous Material
  - Flyers and Calendars, circa 1973-1980 (Box 9)
  - International House Newsletter, 1983-1995 (Box 9)
  - Newsletters from Other Schools, 1995-1999 (Box 9)
  - Clippings, circa 1964-2002, undated (Box 9)
  - Slides and 2 Photographs, circa 1980s (Box 9)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 9)
  - Audiocassette tapes, including Radio Moscow and a NAFSA panel (Box 9)
  - International House Newsletter (oversize), 1963, 1965-1976 (Box 10)
  - International House Newsletter (oversize), 1977-1982 (Box 10)
- Scrapbooks
  - Scrapbook, 1963-1970 (Box 10)
  - Scrapbook, 1971-1975 (Box 11)